hey guys this looks like a fun one we're
trying to find the ratio of the pink
area to the green area let's do this so
first let's try to find the area of
these yin-yang things so let's pull them
out and if we put them together they
should make a circle so it just be half
of that Circle and they don't these make
an ellipse all right scrap that idea
let's try something else so let's draw
the radius right here in fact let's draw
all these radiuses so that we have a
square in the middle right here and
let's focus on that square each of these
sides are two radiuses so we can call it
two R and yes radiuses is the plural of
radius we could also say radi the area
of the square is going to be 2 R * 2 R
that's the same thing as 4 R 2 let's
look at another copy of the square down
here let's pull apart these quarter
circles bring down this green part let's
rotate all these quarter circles to make
a circle the area of this circle will be
P pi r s the area of the green stuff is
then going to be the area of the square
minus the area of this circle now we
don't need the circle anymore so we can
get rid of that let's bring this up here
and this is important so let's put a box
around it let's go back up to this
square up here let's cut the square in
half and let's find the length of this
diagonal well this ends up making a
45459 90 triangle so it ends up being <
TK of 2 * one of these sides so the
diagonal is equal to 2 R < tk2 if you
don't know about the 454590 shortcut
here's the Pythagorean theorem right
here pause it if you want to check it
let's clean all this stuff up and put a
box around this now let's find the area
of our large Circle so we know that the
diagonal the square is equal to 2 < tk2
R and now we don't need the square
anymore and then this right here is a
radius and this right here is a radius
the diameter will be equal to two of the
radiuses plus 2 < tk2 R and if we want
to know what the radius of the largest
circle is we would just divide all that
stuff by two which gives us r + < tk2 r
and now to find the area of this circle
we're going to do PI radius s where this
right here is the radius and then a
binomial squared ends up being the
binomial times itself so we can foil
this out we'll leave the pi out front
and then R * R is R 2 R * < tk2 R is <
tk2 R 2 < tk2 R * R is < tk2 R 2 and <
tk2 R * < tk2 R is = 2 R 2 and then we
can clean this up R 2 + 2 R 2 is 3 R 2
and right here we have 2 < tk2 R 2 so
that would be 2 < tk2 r^ 2 and then we
can distribute the pi so we now have the
area of this largest Circle and we can
put a box around that we're trying to
find the pink area divided by the green
area I think that is what this says so
the pink area is going to be this whole
circle minus this green stuff and then
the green area is going to be this green
stuff we can get rid of these
parentheses and distribute the negative
all six of these terms has an R squ so
we can factor out the r s and then we
can cancel those R squs and then on top
this 3 pi and this 1 Pi can become 4 pi
and now we are done this is the exact
value of the answer and ends up being
approximately
20308 how exciting